flying to the Japanese island of kushu
the bomb was set to be dropped on the
city of kakura as it had a substantial
civilian population of over 130,000
people and contained one of the largest
arsenals in all of Japan as sween's
plane approached kakura however he would
find it heavily obscured by pollution
from the city's factories as well as
smoke drifting over from the neighboring
city of yata which had been firebombed
by American Pilots the previous day
three bombing runs would be made in an
attempt to deliver the nuclear payload
but each time visibility would be too
poor to make the strike and with the
threat of being shot down by Japanese
anti-aircraft fire growing greater with
each attempt the decision was made to
abandon kakura altogether and instead
head to the secondary Target the port
city of
Nagasaki with a population of over
200,000 people Nagasaki was an
industrial city with a rich history of
trade with the West with the Portuguese